Cedric's great question always was, technology is the answer, what is the question?
What is the topic of this year's Swiss Pavilion?
We've done a stroll through a Fun Palace, which is this little booklet here, and
it's still ongoing until November.
It's this year's Biennial curated by Rem Koolhaas and I was invited to curate the
Swiss Pavilion.
And I think, you know, we very often invent the future made with fragments from the
past.
It's something the art historian Panofsky already said and it felt very relevant.
very relevant to protagonists who transcend all boundaries of disciplines or
intensities
and really are in this sense without building objects among the key influences on so
many
artists, architects working today, Lucius Burckhardt and Cedric Price. Both are
serial
inventors, and of course Cedric's Farm Palace is somehow the point of departure of
this
whole model, you know, a sketch for what could be an art center in the 21st century.
And so we call it A Stroll Through a Femme Palace. It's a title which was found in
close
collaboration with artists because I realized with Cedric that he didn't really want
to
be in exhibitions with architects later on in his life. He wanted to be with artists
and that's why we worked a lot in museums and it felt somehow right for Venice to do
an homage to him through and with many artists and at the same time work with Herzog
de Meuron,
architects who are students actually of Lucius Burckhardt on this homage to Lucius
and on the
overall design of the show. Fantastic. Maybe we can also start with the beginning
and just to
speak about your relationship with Cedric. How did you first meet him? In 1999 I
basically visited
for the first time the Serge Anson's museum. It's the museum of the late Serge Anson
who died in 1851
and who has this extraordinary house, had this extraordinary house in Lincoln and
Fields,
where basically more and more life and work blurred and even live work and museum
space
blurred and he sort of during his lifetime developed the house into a museum. And
particularly
the latest part of his life he more and more added elements and you have even
paintings behind the
paintings. It's an incredibly intricate, incredibly dense, incredibly complex
display, probably one of
one of the densest museums I have ever encountered, and it's the artist Kerith Wynne
Evans who
took me there and said, there's something you should know, there is a place you
should
know. And I think that's how many people, many other friends of mine discovered the
Sartre and Sons museum. It's not a museum which would advertise, it's a museum you
sort
of discover through friends telling you about it. So we went there with Kerith and I
was
immediately very obsessed by also the narratives and what happens in the interstices
and I
felt the great potential to maybe get contemporary artists to inhabit the space, to
intervene
these interstices. So we went to see the director, Margaret Richardson, the sister
of J.G. Ballard,
she at the time ran the museum. She was from the very beginning very open to our
ideas and invited
us to guest curate an exhibition for which Douglas Gordon found the title, Retrace
Your Steps,
Remember Tomorrow. So I invited, together with Kerith, maybe 20 artists to come and
live in the
building and make films. Isaac Julian shot the movie there, Steve McQueen did a
sound installation,
Lots of different works were specially created for the house.
Obviously a house museum would produce very different works than a big monumental
museum
because you don't have that sort of overpowering monumentality of the space.
Adorno would say the threshold between the museum and the world is kind of removed
because you're in a live environment and all of a sudden that's where you encounter
art.
You'd have a painting by Richard Hamilton installed on one of the hidden walls
only be seen when the guards open those walls, which they do, I think, every half
hour.
It was actually Richard Hamilton's first visit to the museum. When he and Rita
Donagh,
his partner, came to see the museum, they both said, it's in 1999 that we did this
exhibition at the Sir John's Museum. It must have been around 1998 that I started
to visit Richard Hamilton, trying to convince him to participate in the show. He had
never
been to the Serge Anson's museum and was very interested and came and produced a
poster,
made a painting which was exhibited behind the other paintings in one of these
painting
rooms and also one of Duchamp's glasses, smaller version of the glass, because
obviously
the museum is full of glass, full of mirrors, the Serge Anson Museum.
It's during this very first encounter with Richard Hamilton and Rita Donner near
Oxford
when we went to visit them that I told them about my other show, which is Cities on
the
the Move, which is a show I did with Hohan Roo about Asian cities. Both Rita and
Richard
said in stereo, he's got to meet Cedric. I had heard from Cedric, about Cedric, from
Rem Koolhaas, because obviously Rem Koolhaas is a teacher, and Rem always said that
nobody
has ever changed architecture with fewer means than Cedric. It occurred to me that
Cedric
was working and everyone could actually visit him. Rita and Richard said he's one of
their
close friends and they took the telephone book or they took their address book
actually gave me the
number and said you know ring him so the next day i would ring cedric price and
would go and see him
and it started to be a wonderful wonderful friendship we had quite from the very
beginning
a great a great dialogue he didn't want me to record these conversations at the
beginning so
the first conversation i actually lost it's only after there was a situation of
trust and the
situation of friendship after maybe a year or two that he started to allow me to
record and then
ever since I recorded and filmed him each single time.
Now, at the beginning, Tedrick didn't want to record the conversation,
but we started to meet always early in the morning,
and there would always be kind of 7, 8 o'clock meetings,
and it predated my route to the early club,
but I was always into getting up early.
So I loved those early meetings.
I'd go to half an hour early, have some eggs downstairs,
and then go upstairs to his white room.
You know, it's this marvelous office at Alfred Place,
which is such a great pity that towards the end of his life he lost it.
It was a magical office full of his archives, full of his boxes.
And then upstairs, you know, whilst actually in the middle floor it was completely
full,
upstairs it was completely empty.
It was this pristine white room, which is a room to think, a room for thoughts.
Yeah, and we started to discuss each time, you know, different aspects of his
projects
and I started to find out more about the Fun Palace, which for me, you know, I was
trying
to come up with models to go beyond borders of disciplines and trying to bring art,
science,
music, literature, you know, together.
It was always the great Fetish Project with Van Patten and I wanted to know more
from him.
He told me about John Littlewood, he told me about the connection to cybernetics.
So the sessions wouldn't be very long, we'd always meet for half an hour or an hour,
always talk about the different topics.
He was always very performative, he had an umbrella even if it wouldn't rain,
he would always open the umbrella in the studio.
He always had these amazing striped shirts, unforgettable.
And it was one of my favourite memories of all things I've ever done,
I've ever done, Artie's mornings, you know, with Cedric Price because they were just
so hugely inspiring.
It was like oxygen, it was like oxygen. He gave you oxygen and all of a sudden the
conversation took off
and one would never, one would invent, you know, new things. It was like being next
to a great serial inventor.
It's a bit like when sometimes friends of mine who knew Buckminster Fuller, they
have similar feelings.
I mean at the beginning, a great mystery because there weren't really any books on
him
on him and it felt very difficult to find information, so a legend, you know, a
mystery.
And the more we got to know each other, the more I realized the full scope.
I realized that, you know, he was a kind of an überfigur, that he was really one of
the most
influential thinkers of our time and that the way how he introduced time, the way
how, you know,
he actually completely, you know, changed architecture in the four or five decades
of his work,
work, you know, was the full scope of it became clear to me whilst we got to know
each other.
I knew from the very beginning that he was a legend. I had a great curiosity, I
wanted to know
more, but the more I went there, the more I became completely addicted to find out
more because it
was just in each of these boxes was a world, you know. He had in this studio, he had
these boxes
which were according to different projects. So once we look at the project he had
for the Royal
Avatar, another time we would look at the pop-up Parliament, another time we would
look at,
you know, his InterAction Centre, and then of course his many, many museum projects,
the museum he wanted to do as a museum on the move, the museum on the Queen
Elizabeth.
I mean, many of these projects which later we included in the RECP book.
And so for me, you know, the more I saw these boxes, the more I saw also his
notebooks,
his extraordinary diaries and notebooks, the notebooks full of his drawings.
I was also very fascinated from the beginning, you know, having a visual art
background and
being mostly a curator in the art world, I was amazed by these drawings, which I did
not at all think of kind of architectural, you know, function architectural
drawings.
They're kind of beautiful drawings in their own right. It was one of the great
practice of drawing. I still think, you know, in a way there are so many of these
drawings still to be discovered. These notebooks are full of thousands of these
drawings. So that's a whole other aspect. I got very, very interested not only in
his work, in his writings, in his project, but also in this very, very, in his daily
practice of drawing, of doodling, of sketching, of his stencils, his stamps,
his pamphlets. And then little by little of course came the desire not only to
record
these conversations but also to do a book because I told Cedric that needs to be a
book
which makes your work accessible for a generation of architects who all want to know
more about
you and artists. We did this book with Nick Barley and Pia Kuyzer which was somehow
the
biggest project we worked on and sadly Cedric didn't see it anymore, it took a long
time
to finish the book. But on the way we did lots of other things. I mean the first
collaboration
quite immediately when I went to see him, because it was obviously Richard and Rita
encouraging me to kind of get him involved in Cities on the Move. Cities on the Move
was our sprawling tour on Asian cities with Hohan Ru and it went all over Europe and
the
US and then came to London in 1999, 2000 to the Hayward Gallery and we invited
Cedric
to participate in that because his impact on Asian cities, the way he had also been
thinking that you have a limited lifespan. In Asian cities buildings do
have a limited lifespan and Cedric saw from the beginning that architecture is a bit
like with food, you know, there's a limited lifespan and that sort of whole idea was
there from the beginning. So he had something very Asian about his practice
which I think why in Asia his work was understood so early on because already
in the late 60s Arata Isozaki translated Cedric into Japanese so he was actually
incredibly influential on that whole metabolism generation and on
everything after what happened in Japan, you know, in architecture. So it felt
interesting in an exhibition on Asian cities to get Cedric's take on that and
we showed his market stall so together with Surasi Kusalvang, the artist from
Thailand, he collaborated on a market so the exhibition became actually like a
street market so he brought like the street you know into the Hayward and yet
at the same time you know he helped us a lot to think an exhibition about time
that actually an exhibition wouldn't go from A to B to C but actually it would be
like a complex dynamic system with feedback loops the exhibition would
learn from its previous experience, it would learn from the city where it goes.
So this whole cybernetic idea that he had in the fan palace was somehow injected
into
Cities on the Move.
Cedric kind of made our Cities on the Move show a cybernetic show.
So he was not only present in his Market Stall, the exhibition was designed by Rem
Koolhaas
and Ole Scheren with whom we had a very, very close dialogue.
So I would say they became co-curators of that Hayward show.
And then Cedric was somehow our mentor.
Cedric gave us the idea of it becoming a timeline.
And ever since the exhibition then went to Bangkok,
where we followed Cedric's advice
and left the museum completely
and just had the exhibition in the studios, in the malls.
The exhibition became the city, right?
So because he always said,
it should become like a timeline.
So in a way, yeah, it was instantly,
I mean, it's almost like we were thrown into the water
and swam together in the sense of that.
It was like, how do you call this, it was matchmaking.
I mean, Richard and Rita, Richard Hamilton and Rita Dona
really brought us together and said,
you guys should collaborate.
And so that's what instantly happened.
You know, we see this on the move
and it was a good experience for us.
It was a good experience for him.
He was very excited, I think.
I mean, I was always wondering why he was interested in it.
It was obvious why we were interested in it
because it was an extraordinary opportunity
and an extraordinary experience and an extraordinary gift,
you know, to be able to spend time with him,
get his input in our show,
have him think with us the show.
And I was always wondering what did we give him?
And I think in a way, I think for him,
it was very liberating that I had nothing to do
with the architecture world and that, you know,
he was put in other repair, into other references.
And there were all of a sudden,
he was in an exhibition with a hundred artists,
visual artists from China and, you know,
and Southeast Asia and Japan.
And he found that very amusing and much more amusing
than to be in an architecture biennale, which he hated.
I think there is a wonderful text by Rem Koolhaas, you know, which Rem, we asked
Rem, whom Cedric taught, Cedric was Rem's professor,
we asked Rem to write for the RECP book, for the book I edited, and we asked
actually Isozaki and,
why not, we asked Isozaki and Rem and also Patrick Keeler to write.
Isozaki revisited his text, you know, which he wrote early on, where he introduced
Cedric to Asia,
to Asia and Rem wrote a very short text but very compressed where he talks about
this idea that
Cedric really changed architecture with so few means but that actually these
lapidary epigrams,
these skeletal drawings and also as Rem says his polemical genius for mobilizing the
real against
the pretensions of a still surprisingly megalomaniac profession, that's he changed
the
terrain through this in the 60s and Rem calls him a puritanical Oscar Wilde. It's a
great text.
he sort of said, you know, Cedric used the ridicule and humor to devastating effect
to dismantle one by one the most holy ambitions of an unquestioned profession, the
profession of architecture.
And in a way, it's also part of an extraordinary London, an extraordinary history
where you basically have, of course, Denise Cobb Brown, the Smithsons,
And of course Cedric were sort of all connected to a fascination for the ordinary,
which was
what the Independent Group was about, but also what connected it to Cedric.
And in a way, that actually an attention to the real, the raw and the ugly,
is I think something Rem found very inspiring in Cedric.
There are so many aspects of where Cedric can be a toolbox.
For me, personally, being a curator and a museum director, the great toolbox is
obviously
thinking of museums.
We did together the Nano Museum, which is my portable museum.
I found it in the 90s, which is a little frame, two by three inches, where the
museum could
go anywhere.
The museum would be portable.
Douglas Gordon lost the museum in the pub in Glasgow, so the museum actually died.
You have here a photo of the museum.
It's a Nano Museum.
an exhibition in that where he really defined what the museum for the 21st
century could be. He measured flexibility, he developed
a whole new set of rules of what the museum could be when we developed this
nano museum together. I think for me many of his other ideas like the
museum on a boat, on a cruise ship, the Fun Palace of course as a cultural
center which would not be a place for objects but a place for intensities, a
a place where all intensities could kind of meet, remain very very valid.
But I think somebody who is interested in completely different things will always
find
inspiration from Cedric.
So we wanted this to be like a recipe book.
And the problem obviously was that Cedric forbid us to do this unless it had an
expiry
date.
So the publisher had to agree that actually the book has to best be consumed before
May
the 1st, 2006, because by this date the author may have changed his mind.
So that was a very important aspect of a paradox somehow of doing a book with him.
Because I think that's particularly important if you think about books on Cedric
Nile.
We should always keep in mind that he deeply, deeply mistrusted this idea of it
being frozen.
I think the idea, it's not only the idea of enabling, it's also I think a good hint
we
can find in the project magnets.
Because I mean magnets in Asia, they're used to heal.
There is a whole healing thing with magnets.
And so it's not necessarily, if you think, talks about architectural magnets, it's
not
necessarily adding new buildings to cities, but these magnets could actually
renegotiate
the existing substance, maybe heal it, maybe repoll it, give it a different kind of
significance.
And he had this idea, which he told me very often, that he wanted to add magnets to
the
city to re-dynamize it, to reinvent it.
And I think that sort of whole idea that we can actually, we live in an age of more
and
more limited resources and I think it's not necessarily about permanently adding new
buildings
but maybe also thinking about what we could do with the existing and how the
existing
could actually be redefined. That's what the idea of the US found is I think another
kind
of, it's something we discuss a lot in Venice.
For me it will always be the front palace because it's closest to my heart because
I've
always felt what is missing and it's interesting, I mean Ernst Bloch when pushed
hard by Adorno
in a conversation about what would be utopia, he defined utopia as something that's
missing.
And I still think if we think what's missing in our time, it is these
pluridisciplinary
institutions because bigger institutions, whenever they wanted to bring all the
disciplines
together, all the different art forms together, it then again became
departmentalized.
And I think this idea of having an institution or an institute where you wouldn't
have objects,
you'd have it away, nothing would be frozen, but you would have a situation where
the different
– the word discipline is kind of ugly because it means that there are disciplines or
disciplinary
boundaries so we'd rather talk maybe about intensities. So in a way, a structure
where
all these different intensities could encounter, where you have fast lanes and slow
lanes,
where you have silent zones and noisy zones, I think remains for me the very potent
and
powerful idea, particularly it was the dialogue between Cedric as an architect and
urbanist
and John Littlewood as a theatre director. And then an amazing think tank like
Yehudi
Menuhin from music like Gordon Parske for cybernetics. And I think in a way they got
quite close to building it. I think the history of museums, art centres would have
been a
different one had that project gone ahead. And for me it remains certainly my
favourite
project of Cedric. But there is also the pottery think-bath which are close to my
heart because
I think besides inventing this sort of art centre of intensities which we need for
the
I think there is also a missing school and what would a Black Mountain College for
the 21st century be?
It would probably be on wheels, eventually not on wheels but certainly mobile.
And I think this whole idea that he wanted to use with the Potteries Thinkbelt,
an abandoned railway line in Staffordshire in England and basically revitalize, like
with the magnets, you know, where the magnets can heal but can also
re-dynamize. He wanted to re-dynamize this abandoned railway line and make it into a
classroom on the move. It's a very beautiful idea.
Yeah, I mean it's in the world of the Fun Palace. It's the idea that he, you know,
it was a delight.
And for me, it's among the happiest moments is to experience a morning with Cedric.
It was just about the pure delight, the delight of being alive, the delight of
inventing ideas,
the delight of being so free. It was his incredible freedom, you know, he had,
of not having any kind of constraints to his practice. He was free.
Like the birds in the aviary, I mean, it was always his idea.
it's almost like a metaphor for his life and for his work, is his idea of not
imprisoning practice.
I think in a way, if you look at the aviary, one of the great masterpieces which he
built with Newby and Snowdon,
the aviary in the London Zoo, is initially actually destined to fly out of the zoo
according to the mood swings of the birds.
So should the birds decide they could fly away with the aviary.
So it's the anti-Zoo so to say.
And in a way it was then only later that he, you know, in a second round so to say,
that
he agreed that the aviary would actually be fixed, but that the upper parts would
move
in the wind, you could potentially imagine that the birds can move, it was kind of
like,
you know, a flexible architecture.
But if you think about this, it actually became very important for the Swiss
pavilion because
what could we do with the pavilion to keep this spirit of the birds being able to
fly
away.
a bow-wow designed on the roof a kind of aviary for the Swiss Pavilion, but it had
no glass,
it had no vitrine, so basically there were no birds inside because the birds in any
way
had flown out.
So the visitor was inside and could hear the birds, and the birds were in the tree,
the
birds were free.
And I think that was for me almost like perfect for a bow-wow, to do that as an
homage to
because it was the fun palace, it was what the aviary was always meant to be.
And I think this idea also of not...
because very often I think, and you see that also with exhibition spaces,
that very often it can be actually an imposition in which someone has to operate.
And Cedric wanted rather this idea of delight to always be there.
And it could be with a building or without a building,
but it could very often be that the building would spoil that delight.
So, and I think that's a very important part.
And also this idea of play, I think,
goes hand in hand with this.
I mean, Robert Louis Stevenson once said,
"'Art is like when children play,
"'but it has the seriousness of playing children.'"
That's how I always felt in the presence of Cedric.
Okay, so once on a rainy Wednesday morning,
I arrived there at seven and had a coffee
and some ex-dancers waiting for him to arrive.
And at 7.30, we would start the meeting
and he would be compelled to talk about his idea
of having a city, having a part of the city where umbrellas would pop up.
I don't know what that project is called, I think we have it in the book.
It's a project where all of a sudden, you know, when it rains the umbrellas would go
up.
So we talked about this idea with Cedric at 7.30, because it was a rainy Wednesday
morning.
We talked about the idea that actually he had suggested that streets could be
covered by umbrellas
and they would pop up when it rains and then he wouldn't have to own an umbrella.
The umbrella would be for everyone, it would be a collective umbrella.
I mean it's very much also this idea of Buckwheat and Sofulla that we don't
necessarily have to own architecture,
that we don't have to own buildings, that we don't have to own a car,
that it's more like a service as Buckwheat and Sofulla said.
So he had this idea of the umbrella as an urban service and then all of a sudden,
out of the blue in his office produced a beautifully stripped kind of umbrella which
matched his shirt
and started to open it.
So I filmed him whilst he opened the umbrella, whilst obviously we were inside, it
was raining outside.
So it was like a performance and we then started to talk about the Serge Ranson's
museum because I told him that, you know,
that's why I came to see him.
But obviously before I could even start to talk about the project,
he had sort of kidnapped me on this idea of the umbrella because of the rain.
And so it was always very, very, you know, there were not just meetings where we
talked about projects,
it was like a flanerie, it was a stroll.
It's like I want to walk with him, I walk through his ideas.
And he was obviously documented through these magical boxes.
The boxes inside, there wasn't really all of them, just all the documents thrown in,
but it was classified according to projects.
So just pick a box and then show.
And often we would also look at his notebooks with his amazing drawings.
That would be another form of walk, of stroll.
I would then finally get him focused on the Serge Anson's exhibition that morning.
We would go from the umbrella to the rain to the Serge Anson's museum.
And I remember he told me that what he loved about the Serge Anson's museum
that it used to be that during rainy days people were not allowed to enter
because the museum didn't want people to bring the rain with the shoes wet into the
museum.
So on rainy or snowy days the museum was closed.
It's a very kind of eccentric way of defining opening hours of the museum.
But that was true until quite recently.
So we entered the Zones Museum, it was about the rain,
and he then had this wonderful, wonderful idea.
He said, you know, if you look at this museum it's more like a conversation piece
because when you go to a big museum, and that's the great thing about smaller
museums,
It's also so exciting, we have this conversation today here at the Serpentine
Gallery, and I'm
co-director here at the Serpentine Gallery, and Julia Paton-Jones is director, and
very
often when Julia and I talk, you know, this is a former tea house, and we find it
interesting that actually it's a place, a house museum, or the scale of a house,
leads
to conversations, much more than a monumental place, it's got a threshold.
And so I think Cedric was interested in this idea that the Serge Anson's museum,
more than
any other museum, is a conversation piece, and when people enter the museum they
have
a conversation with the guard at the entrance.
So Zedek said all of these guards will have great stories, stories of visitors,
stories
with objects.
So he basically had me interview every single guard and write down the stories and
bring
it to him.
And then he made a drawing for each single of these guards and the drawing was made
into
a badge and they had to wear or could wear if they wanted their own story.
So his piece in the exhibition was a trigger for conversations.
It was such a delight.
He basically gave to each guard their own story drawn, and they of course all loved
it and put it on.
And obviously that prompted the viewer then to ask the guard, what's that thing
here?
And then the guard could tell the story, and would each time tell a different story.
I mean, it's a fantastic invention.
The question of what is relevant about Cedric cannot be answered in one answer,
because
I think there are so many dimensions to Cedric.
It's almost like superstring theory.
I mean, I think one, and superstring theory has 11 dimensions.
I think one of the dimensions is certainly this idea of the fun palace, of a
cultural
institution where he said that it's in a way a laboratory, yet it also serves as a
harvest
for the quiet eye.
It's slow and fast.
It sort of produces difference.
It's an engine for difference in a maybe more and more homogenized culture.
So in a way, I think that is something which is very relevant for the 21st century.
I think what is also very relevant for the 21st century are his ideas of the school.
I think the idea of the Potteries Thinkbelt as a kind of a new possibility of
injecting
basically a school which remains physical but which can happen sort of in between
remains
a great model, I think.
And we could go through all his projects.
I also think that the pop-up parliament should happen one day.
I mean, it's this idea that we have lots of institutions which are only used once a
month
or once a week, but which are there all the time.
So if these institutions would only pop up when they're needed,
and they would not be there, you know, it's sort of interesting as well.
I think what is also a very important part of his legacy is this last project for
New York,
which I think needs to be emphasized more because it's such a visionary project
where he decided to do nothing, where he just defined this empty space
as a kind of space which should, you know, where we should not build,
where nothing should be built, where it would be almost like injecting oxygen into a
city like Manhattan.
And I think that obviously given the fact that we run out of oxygen in our
metropolis,
is a very important project.
I think Cedric's legacy are these thousands of drawings which each single of them is
a spark.
And I think who knows what they will trigger in the future when young architects or
artists see them.
I think also at the moment when drawing, when Marmora's drawing happens on the
internet
and happens on the computer, I think his sort of doodling activity is a very
important thing
because you know handwriting risks to disappear.
I think Cedric's entire work is about the hand drawn kind of sketches and all of
that
and so I think that's another very important kind of you know legacy.
I think also his idea that we don't necessarily have to add object is important.
I mean if Tino Segal talks about this idea that art you know and it's similarly true
was for architecture from the 19th century to the 1960s of the 20th century, you
know,
had sort of this evolutive history, but it was always connected to objects. And then
in the 60s you've got conceptual art, you've got a questioning of the object. I
think in
a way Cedric, parallel to conceptual art, you know, in the art world started to
question
the object in architecture. And I think today there's a whole other kind of
necessity for
that because we live in a world where we realize more and more that resources are
limited.
We realize more and more that there is a danger of extinction if we are not more
careful with
our resources and with our environment, which is why this year we are doing with
Gustav
Messer the Extinction Marathon.
I think in a way Cedric is renegotiating.
The Magnet City is a very homoeopathic project.
It's very 21st century.
It is our idea that we can actually recharge the batteries, that we can recharge the
cities
without necessarily wasting energies and wasting resources.
So it's very much, I think Cedric's practice in this sense,
you know, connects, even if he grew out very much
out of the optimism also of the 60s, you know,
it connects also very, very much to the current moment
where we are realizing, you know,
the big, big danger of unlimited growth.
And Binswanger as an economist
thinking about the limits of growth.
So I think, yeah, the 21st century
is a Cedric Price century.